<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
distributed with this work for additional information
regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
"License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
software distributed under the License is distributed on an
"AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
specific language governing permissions and limitations
under the License.
-->

<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
  <properties>
    <title>Welcome To Apache Giraph</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Distributed graph processing with Giraph">
<p><i>Giraph</i> (pronounced like the animal giraffe) is an iterative graph processing system.  As an example use case, Facebook uses Giraph to analyze its social graph in production. Giraph is motivated by the Turing Award winning [<a href="#turing">1</a>] elegant Bulk Synchronous Parallel (BSP) model of distributed computation by Valiant [<a href="#bsp">2</a>], and the Pregel graph processing system [<a href="#pregel">3</a>] from Google that evidenced that an appropriately extended BSP model is useful for large-scale graph computation. Giraph distinguishes itself by being an open source, scalable graph processing platform with a growing community of users worldwide. You are welcome to explore the <i>User Docs</i> menu above that explain how to process graphs with Giraph.</p>
</section>


<section name="News">

<ul>
  <li>Official releases of Giraph may be downloaded from an <a href="http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/giraph/">Apache mirror</a>. Soon we will also publish our release artifacts to Apache's Maven repositories to make it easier to include Giraph in your projects.</li>
  <li><strong>May 6, 2013: Giraph 1.0.0 is now released!</strong> Please pick up a copy at <a href="http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/giraph/giraph-1.0.0">here</a>.</li>
  <li><strong>February 6, 2012: Giraph 0.1-incubating released.</strong> The Giraph PPMC is excited to announce that version 0.1 has been released. Grab a copy of the archived release <a href="http://archive.apache.org/dist/incubator/giraph">here</a>.</li>
</ul>

</section>

<section name="Getting involved">

<p>Giraph is a new project and we're looking to quickly build a community of users and contributors. All types of help is appreciated: contributing patches, writing documentation, posing and answering questions on the mailing list, even <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/GIRAPH-4">graphic design</a>. Here's how to get involved with Giraph (or any Apache project):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Subscribe to the <a href="mail-lists.html">mailing lists</a>, particularly the user and dev list, and follow their activity for a while to get a feel for the state of the project and what the community is working on.</li>
  <li>Browse through <a href="issue-tracking.html">Giraph's JIRA</a>, our issue tracking system, to find issues you may be interested in working on. To help new contributors pitch in quickly, we maintain a <a href="http://bit.ly/newbie_apache_giraph_issues">set of JIRAs</a> that focus on getting new contributors started with the mechanics of generating a patch &#151; downloading the source, changing a couple of lines, creating a patch, verifying its correctness, uploading it to JIRA and working with the community &#151; rather than deep technical issues within Giraph itself. These are good issues with which to join the community. Take a look at the section on <a href="generating_patches.html">generating patches</a> for detailed instructions on creating patches.</li>
  <li>Try out the examples and play with Giraph on your cluster. Be sure to ask questions on the mailing list or open new JIRAs if you run into issues with your particular configuration.</li>
</ul>

</section>


<section name="References">

<ol>
<li id="turing">Leslie Valiant: The 2010 A.M. Turing Award (<a href="http://amturing.acm.org/award_winners/valiant_2612174.cfm">link</a>)</li>
<li id="bsp">Leslie Valiant: A bridging model for parallel computation. Communications of the ACM, Vol. 33(8) (1990) pp. 103-111 (<a href="http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=79173.79181">link</a>)</li>
<li id="pregel">Grzegorz Malewicz, Matthew H. Austern, Aart J.C Bik, James C. Dehnert, Ilan Horn, Naty Leiser, Grzegorz Czajkowski: Pregel: a system for large-scale graph processing. ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data (2010) pp. 135-146 (<a href="http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1807184">link</a>)</li>
</ol>

</section>

  </body>
</document>
